Guide to the John Henry and Anna Botsford Comstock papers, 1833-1955,
Comstock, John Henry and Anna Botsford papers,
- Wood engravings, sketches, drawings, and photographs by Anna Botsford Comstock, 1891-1930
  - Watercolors, Undated
    - Watercolors, Undated (Box 11)
    - Garden with tower in the background, Undated (Box 19)
    - Italian village scene, girl at right, Undated (Box 19)
  - Sketches, Undated
    - Sketches used in Comstock publications, Undated (Box 11)
    - Pen and ink sketches, Undated (Box 12)
      From a Manual for the Study of Insects and Handbook of Nature Study by Anna Botsford Comstock
    - Pen and ink sketches from the Handbook of Nature Study, Undated (Box 19)
      - Witch Hazel (letter W), Undated (Box 19)
      - Dragonfly (letter D), Undated (Box 19)
      - Ichneumom fly (letter I), Undated (Box 19)
      - Inchworm (letter I), Undated (Box 19)
      - Elephant's head (letter P), Undated (Box 19)
      - Cricket (letter I), Undated (Box 19)
      - Hummingbird (letter I), Undated (Box 19)
      - Spider's Web (letter P), Undated (Box 19)
      - Flowers and Moth (letter I), Undated (Box 19)
      - Chipmunk or Squirrel (letter W), Undated (Box 19)
      - Seed Pod flower (letter L), Undated (Box 19)
      - Insect crawling up the letter P, Undated (Box 19)
      - Toad with fly (letter W), Undated (Box 19)
      - Spider in a hot air balloon (letter I), Undated (Box 19)
  - Photographs and slides, Undated
    - Photographs and sketches used in Comstock publications, Undated; 24.5 x 17 cm; 35 drawn illustrations, 37 photographic illustrations; Most of these illustrations are mounted on board and include typewritten captions or handwritten notes about size for publishing. (Box 13)
      Birds
      Pen and ink drawings
      Gelatin silver prints
    - Photographs and sketches used in Comstock publications, Undated; Various; 21 folders; Many with labels or diagrammatic annotations. (Box 14)
      Insects
      Cyanotypes
    - Lecture slides, 1897-1930; 8.5 x 10.2 cm; 46 slides; 15 slides have applied color. (Box 16)
      Used by Anna Botsford Comstock during her Nature Study classes.
      Plants
      Owls
      Osprey
      Gelatin silver transparencies
      photographic transparencies
    - Mixed photos, Undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
      Including a family of Flathead "Indians" and Cornell Insectary
  - Mixed media, Undated
    - Butterfly, Undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Butterfly, Undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Butterflies and moths, Undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Dandelion an butterfly, Undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Luna moth and others at night, Undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Flowers and butterflies, Undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - "First Impression" woman and lions, Undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
      from C.S. King
    - Mythological water creatures, Undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
      from F.S. king
    - Wood engravings and drawings by Anna Botsford Comstock, Undated (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Microfilm
  - John Henry Comstock professional correspondence, November 1878-July 1888 (Reel 1)
  - John Henry Comstock professional correspondence, August 1888-July 1890 (Reel 2)
  - John Henry Comstock professional correspondence, July 1890-October 1891 (Reel 3)
  - John Henry Comstock professional correspondence, November 1891-October 1893 (Reel 4)
  - John Henry Comstock professional correspondence, November 1893-September 1926 (Reel 5)